Guide to the A. L. Langellier papers, 1875-1917.
Langellier, A. L. papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
A. L. Langellier papers, 1875-1917.
434
Langellier, A. L.
6.8 cubic ft.
Correspondence, Printed Material, Publications.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Account books, correspondence, pamphlets, and newspapers relating to the work of Langellier in the land industry.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Proprietor of the Iroquois County Times, and chief clerk of the land office of the Northern Pacific Railroad, St. Paul, Minnesota.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Account books, correspondence, pamphlets, and newspapers relating to the Iroquois County Times. Correspondence of Langellier as promoter of the Michigan Syndicate Timber Lands (later Peters-Langellier Land Company) regarding purchase from the Louisville and Nashville Railroad Company; management and sale of 600,000 acres of west Florida timber lands located in Wakulla, Taylor, Washington, Walton, Santa Rosa, Milton, and Calhoun Counties, showing difficulties resulting from timber stealing, squatting, trespass, problems of securing competent managers, making tax payments, sale of timber, turpentine, sand, gravel, sales and leasing arrangements, and includes instances of litigation. Another series of letters deals with the reclamation of 2136 acres of Fulton County, Havana, Illinois swampland and its transformation into farmland; information on renting these lands to tenants; letters detailing the clash of Langellier with Lacey drainage district tax commissioners over assessments and the resulting litigation. Collection also pertains to real estate throughout the West; purchase of California swamp and marsh land located on Southern Pacific Railroad property; correspondence which relates to purchases from Choctaw, Oklahoma, and Gulf Railroad Co.; rental and sale of Tama County, Iowa farm land to proposed investment in Kansas oil land; clearing Jackson County, Wisconsin; correspondence with American Colonization Company of Cedar Rapids, Iowa.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Langellier, A. L.; American Colonization Company (Cedar Rapids, Iowa); Choctaw, Oklahoma and Gulf Railroad Company.; Louisville and Nashville Railroad Company.; Michigan Syndicate Timber Lands.; Northern Pacific Railway Company.; Peters-Langellier Land Company.; Southern Pacific Railroad Company.
Titles:
Iroquois County Times.
Subjects:
Real property -- Minnesota.; Lumber industry -- Florida.; Real property -- Iowa.; Real property -- California.; Real property -- Florida.; Real property -- Wisconsin.; Real property -- Illinois.; Reclamation of land -- Illinois.; Reclamation of land -- California.; Railroad companies -- Minnesota.; Railroad companies -- Iowa.; Labor supply.; Taxation -- Florida.; Taxation -- Illinois.; Land use -- Florida.; Land use -- California.; Land use -- Iowa.; Land use -- Illinois.; Land use -- Florida.; Timber -- Florida.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Records (Volume 1)
- Records, 1875, 1885-1886 (Box 1)
  Includes letterbook of outgoing letters as chief clerk of the Land Office of the N.P.R.R., St. Paul Minnesota on sale of company lands.
- Records, 1900 (Box 2)
- Records, 1900 (Box 3)
- Records, 1900-1901 (Box 4)
- Records, 1900-1901 (Box 5)
- Records, 1901-1902 (Box 6)
- Records, 1901-1902 (Box 7)
- Records, 1902 (Box 8)
- Records, 1902-1903 (Box 9)
- Records, 1903 (Box 10)
- Records, 1903 (Box 11)
- Records, 1904 (Box 12)
- Records, 1904 (Box 13)
- Records, 1905 (Box 14)
- Records, 1905, 1916 (Box 15)
- Records, 1906, 1916 (Box 16)
- Records, 1917 (Box 17)